intro_variable = {
    "Definition": "Variables in math are symbols, often letters, that represent different values in various situations. They help us understand and solve problems with changing values. ",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Evaluate 6 + x when x = 3",
                "Answer": "6 + 3 = 9",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

sub_eval_ex = {
    "Definition": "Evaluating expressions with multiple variables involves substituting given values for each variable and simplifying the expression. \
    By replacing variables with their corresponding values, we can easily compute the result of expressions, even for more complex examples with multiple terms and operations.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Evaluate p/4 + pq when p = 8 and q = 6",
                "Answer": "8/4 + 8*6=50",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

com_like_term = {
    "Definition": "In simple addition we learned to add all the numbers together to get a sum. \
    In algebra, numbers are sometimes attached to variables and we need to make sure that the variables are alike before we add the numbers.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Combine the like terms to create an equivalent expression: -2x - x + 8",
                "Answer": "-2x - x + 8 = -3x + 8",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

intro_eq_ex = {
    "Definition": "We find equivalent expressions by combining like terms and using the distributive property.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Which expressions are equivalent to p + q + p + q + p",
                "Answer": "2*p+3*q",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }


div_by_zero = {
    "Definition": "We find equivalent expressions by combining like terms and using the distributive property.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Which expressions are equivalent to p + q + p + q + p",
                "Answer": "2*p+3*q",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

s1 = {
    "Definition": "We will use a scale to try to achieve balance and help explain why we do the same thing to both sides of an equation, even when the variable appears on both sides",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Solve for b: 7b-15=5b-3",
                "Answer": "7b - 15 = 5b - 3 <=> 7b - 5b - 15 = 5b - 5b - 3 <=> 2b - 15 = -3 <=> 2b - 15 + 15 = -3 + 15 <=> 2b = 12 <=> b = 6",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

s2 = {
    "Definition": "When we perform operations to manipulate equations, some operations produce equivalent equations, while others don't necessarily produce equivalent equations. \
    When we're solving an equation, we need to use operations that guarantee equivalence. ",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Solve for r. r/2 - 3 = 3*(4-3/2*r). Give an exact answer. ",
                "Answer": "r/2 - 3 = 3*(4-3/2*r) <=> r/2 - 3 = 12 - 9/2*r <=> 5*r = 15 <=> r = 3",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

s3 = {
    "Definition": "See how some equations have one solution, others have no solutions, and still others have infinite solutions.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "How many solutions does the following equation have? -5(z+1)=-2z+10",
                "Answer": "-5(z+1)=-2z+10 <=> z = -5. Hence, exactly one solution",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

s4 = {
    "Definition": "Sal solves the equations ax+3x=bx+5 and a(5-x)=bx-8 for x. Note that these equations include other unknowns (a and b) but we solve them for x.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Solve for z. Assume the equation has a solution for z. -cz+6z=tz+83",
                "Answer": "Subtract t*z from both sides of the equation. -c*z + 6*z - t*z = 83. Factor z out of -c*z + 6*z -t*z . z*( - c + 6 - t ) = 83 Divide each term in z*( - c + 6 - t )  = 83 by - c + 6 - t and simplify. z=-83/(c-6+t)",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 5
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

s5 = {
    "Definition": "We solve several multi-step linear inequalities. When solving an equation, our goal is to find the value of the variable that makes the equation true.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "",
                "Answer": "22q+73>52q+63 <=> 22q >52q-10 (Subtract 73 from both sides) <=> -30q > -10 (Subtract 52q from both sides) <=> 30q<10 (Multiply both sides by -1) <=> q<1/3 (Divide both sides by 30 and simplify)",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

s6 = {
    "Definition": "A compound inequality is an inequality that combines two simple inequalities. Let's take a look at some examples.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Solve for x: 12x+7<-11 OR 5x-8>40",
                "Answer": "Solve the first inequality we get x<-3/2. The second inequality we get x>48/5. Hence we get x<-3/2 or x>48/5",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

unit1 = {
    "Definition": "Rate conversion in integrated math refers to the process of converting between different units of measurement when dealing with rates or ratios.\
     It involves changing the units of measurement while maintaining the same underlying relationship between quantities.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "A sheet of glass has a density of 2.5 g/cm³. What is the density of the glass in kilograms per cubic meter (kg/m³)?",
                "Answer": "1 g/cm³ = 1000 kg/m³. Given that the density of the glass is 2.5 g/cm³, we can multiply it by the conversion factor to get the density in kg/m³: Density in kg/m³ = 2.5 g/cm³ * 1000 kg/m³ Density in kg/m³ = 2500 kg/m³ Therefore, the density of the glass is 2500 kg/m³.",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

unit2 = {
    "Definition": "When using formulas to calculate real-world quantities, we need to make sure our units are consistent. \
    In order to compare which rate is faster, we need to convert one of the rates to units that match the other rate.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "The formula for the volume of a pyramid is (1/3) * A * h, where A is the area of the pyramid's base and h is its height. \
                The base of the Great Pyramid of Giza is about 53,000 square meters, and its height is about 150 meters. \
                What calculation will give us the estimated volume of the Great Pyramid of Giza in cubic meters?",
                "Answer": "53000*150/3",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
unit3 = {
    "Definition": "In word problems that involve multiple quantities, we can use the units of the quantities to guide our solution.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Lennox owns a big apple orchard, and she ships her apples to various markets using a fleet of trucks. \
                Every week, each truck goes on 3 trips, and for each trip, Lennox earns 300 dollars. \
                On a single trip, a truck delivers 50 packs, and each pack contains 12 kilograms of apples. \
                In total, Lennox sells apples worth 4,500 dollars in a week. How many trucks are in Lennox's fleet?",
                "Answer": "Let's assume there are x trucks in Lennox's fleet. Every week, each truck goes on 3 trips, so the total number of trips made by all the trucks is 3x. Therefore, Total earnings = 300 * 3x We are given that the total earnings in a week are 4,500 dollars. So: 4,500 = 300 * 3x. Solve for x: 4,500 = 900x. So: x = 5 Therefore, Lennox's fleet consists of 5 trucks.",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

leg1 = {
    "Definition": "Learn about a class of equations in two variables that's called 'linear equations.' They are called that way because their graph is a line.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "The equation is '-4x - y = 24'. Complete the missing value in the solution to the equation.: (?, 8)",
                "Answer": "-8",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
leg2 = {
    "Definition": "Slope is a measure of the steepness of a line. Slope = Δy/Δx",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "What is the slope of the line through the points (6, 9) and (7, 1)?",
                "Answer": "Slope = Δy/Δx=(1-9)/(7-6)=-8",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
leg3 = {
    "Definition": "When two points have the same y-value, it means they lie on a horizontal line. The slope of such a line is 0, and you will also find this by using the slope formula. ",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "What is the slope of the line x=9?",
                "Answer": "Undefined since Δx = 0",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
leg4 = {
    "Definition": "The x-intercept is the point where a line crosses the x-axis, and the y-intercept is the point where a line crosses the y-axis.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Determine the intercepts of the line represented by the equation: -5x - 4y = 10",
                "Answer": "-5x - 4y = 10 are (-2, 0) for the x-intercept and (0, -2.5) for the y-intercept.",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

fle1 = {
    "Definition": "Slope-intercept form (y=mx+b) of linear equations highlights the slope (m) and the y-intercept (b) of a line.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "A big ship drops its anchor. E represents the anchor's elevation relative to the water's surface (in meters) as a function of time tt (in seconds).\
                 E = -2.4t + 75 How far does the anchor drop every 5 seconds?",
                "Answer": "At t = 0 seconds: E = -2.4(0) + 75 E = 75 meters; At t = 5 seconds: E = -2.4(5) + 75 E = 75 - 12 E = 63 meters;\
                 Distance dropped = E(t = 0) - E(t = 5) = 75 - 63 = 12 meters",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

fle3 = {
    "Definition": "Slope-intercept is a specific form of linear equations in two variables: y = mx + b In this form,\
     'm' represents the slope of the line, and 'b' represents the y-intercept.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Complete the equation of the line through (3, -8) and (6, -4)",
                "Answer": "Slope = (-4 - (-8)) / (6 - 3) = (-4 + 8) / (6 - 3) = 4 / 3; Using the point (3, -8): -8 = (4/3)(3) + b => b = -12; Therefore: y = (4/3)x - 12",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
fle4 = {
    "Definition": "Point-slope is a specific form of linear equations in two variables: y - b = m(x - a). \
    When an equation is written in this form, 'm' gives the slope of the line and '(a, b)' is a point the line passes through. This form is derived from the slope formula.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Complete the point-slope equation of the line through (-8, -8) and (-7, 9). y - 9 = ?",
                "Answer": "Slope = (9 - (-8)) / (-7 - (-8)) = (9 + 8) / (-7 + 8) = 17 / 1 = 17; Using the point (-7, 9), we have: y - 9 = 17(x - (-7)). \
                So, the completed point-slope equation of the line passing through (-8, -8) and (-7, 9) is: y - 9 = 17(x + 7)",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

fle5 = {
    "Definition": "This is the standard form of linear equations in two variables: ax+by=c. Usually in this form a,b, and c are all integers",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "What is y - 8 = 3(x + 1) written in standard form?",
                "Answer": "-3x+y=11",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

soe1 = {
    "Definition": "a collection of two or more equations that are to be solved simultaneously, with the goal of finding values for the variables that satisfy all the equations in the system",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "y=-4x+6; 3x+4y=-2; is (2,2) a solution of the system?",
                "Answer": "No since the second is incorrect",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

soe2 = {
    "Definition": "The substitution method is a technique for solving systems of linear equations.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "-7x-6y=4; x=-3y+8; What is the value of x and y",
                "Answer": "Plugging in -3y+8 for x in -7x-6y=4, we get -7(-3y+8)-6y=4. \
                Simplifying further, we have 21y-56-6y=4, which becomes 15y=60 when combined. Solving for y, we find y=4. \
                Substituting this value back into the second equation, we can solve for x. \
                Plugging in y=4 in x=-3y+8, we get x=-3(4)+8, which simplifies to x=-4. Therefore, the values of x and y are -4 and 4, respectively.",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
soe3 = {
    "Definition": "Systems of equations that have the same solution are called equivalent systems. \
    Given a system of two equations, we can produce an equivalent system by replacing one equation \
    by the sum of the two equations, or by replacing an equation by a multiple of itself. \
    In contrast, we can be sure that two systems of equations are not equivalent if we know that a solution of the one is not a solution of the other.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "System A: {8x-3y=0;2x+7y=3}; System B: {8x-3y=0; 8x+28y=12}. How can we get System B from System A?",
                "Answer": "Replace one equation with a multiple of itself",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

soe4 = {
    "Definition": "The elimination method is a technique for solving systems of linear equations.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Which of these strategies would eliminate a variable in the system of equations? System: {8x + 5y = -7; -7x + 6y = -4}",
                "Answer": "Multiply the top equation by 66, multiply the bottom equation by -5, then add the equations.",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
soe5 = {
    "Definition": "One solution. A system of linear equations has one solution when the graphs intersect at a point. No solution. A system of linear equations has no solution when the graphs are parallel.\
    Infinite solutions. A system of linear equations has infinite solutions when the graphs are the exact same line.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "How many solutions does the system have? System: {12x+9y=-36; 4x+3y=-12} ",
                "Answer": "The two equations have the same slope-intercept form, which means they are represented by the same line! Since both equations are represented by the same line, they intersect infinitely many times, so the system has infinitely many solutions.",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

soe6 = {
    "Definition": "Systems of equations can be used to solve many real-world problems.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Ben is 20 years older than Daniel. Ben and Daniel first met two years ago. Three years ago, Ben was 3 times as old as Daniel.",
                "Answer": "Let Ben's current age be b and Daniel's current age be d: b = d+20; Three years ago, Ben was b-3 years old, and Daniel was d - 3 years old: b-3 = 3(d-3) => Solving 2 above linear equations: d = 13",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

isg1 = {
    "Definition": "the process of verifying whether a given pair of values for two variables satisfies or fulfills an inequality statement involving those variables.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Is (-5,-5) a solution of y>=-2x+4?",
                "Answer": "No since the inequality does not hold for x=-5 and y=-5",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }


isg3 = {
    "Definition": "",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "A colony of flowers is pollinated by hummingbirds and sunbirds. \
                Let H represent the number of hummingbirds and S represent the number of sunbirds that must pollinate the colony so it can survive until next year.\
                6H+4S>74. This year, 8 hummingbirds pollinated the colony. \
                What is the least number of sunbirds that must pollinate the colony to ensure that it will survive until next year?",
                "Answer": "Replace H with 8, we have S > 6.5. Therefore, at least 7 sunbirds must pollinate the colony.",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

f2 = {
    "Definition": "Given an input, a function with produce an output",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "h(t)=-20+11t. What is h(11)?",
                "Answer": "h(11)=-20+11*11=101",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }

f4 = {
    "Definition": "Equations and functions are not the same thing, but they can be related in several ways. ",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "For a given input value x, the function g outputs a value y to satisfy the following equation. -4x-6=-5y+2. Write a formula for g(x) in terms of x",
                "Answer": "g(x) = 4/5*x + 8/5",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
f5 = {
    "Definition": "Learn how to interpret expressions that contain a function within a real-world context.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Alek went for a walk. D(t) models the distance Alek walked (in kilometers) after t hours. What does the statement D(0.5)<D(1)−D(0.5) mean?",
                "Answer": "The distance Alek walked during the first half hour is shorter than the distance he walked during the following half hour.",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
f7 = {
    "Definition": "The domain of a function is the set of all possible inputs for the function.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "h(x)=sqrt(x-10). What is the domain of h?",
                "Answer": "All real values of x such that x>=10",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
f8 = {
    "Definition": "Checking whether a given set of points can represent a function. \
    For the set to represent a function, each domain element must have one corresponding range element at most.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Omar is an event promoter. \
                The table compares the number of people who said they would attend an event and the number of people who actually attended it, for the last few events Omar promoted.\
                 Can the actual attendance be represented as a function of the planned attendance? Table: Planned attendance: {150, 220, 370, 220, 200}, Actual attendance: {130, 200, 330, 200, 130}",
                "Answer": "The input value 220 appears twice in the table, but both times it's mapped to the output value 200, hence yes",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
f13 = {
    "Definition": "Average rate of change tells us how much the function changed per a single time unit, over a specific interval. ",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "Vera uploaded a hilarious video to a funny videos website. V(t) models the number of views the video got as a function of time t (in hours). t : {5,10,20}, V(t)={70,180,500}. When did the number of views increase faster?",
                "Answer": "Between 10 and 20 hours",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 4
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }
f14 = {
    "Definition": "Inverse functions, in the most general sense, are functions that 'reverse' each other.",
    "QA Queue": [
            {
                "Question": "What is the inverse of the function g(x)=−3(x+6)?",
                "Answer": "Step 1: Replace g(x) with y. y = -3(x + 6) Step 2: Swap x and y. x = -3(y + 6) Step 3: Solve for y. x = -3y - 18 Step 4: Isolate y. 3y = -x - 18 Divide both sides by 3: y = (-x - 18) / 3 Simplifying further: y = -x/3 - 6 Therefore, the inverse of the function g(x) = -3(x + 6) is given by f(x) = -x/3 - 6.",
                "Type": "Narrative",
                "Difficulty": 5
            }
        ],
    "Rate": 1,
    }


math_1_part_1 = {
    "Algebra foundations": [
        {
            "Introduction to variables": intro_variable
        },
        {
            "Substitution and evaluating expressions": sub_eval_ex
        },
        {
            "Combining like terms": com_like_term
        },
        {
            "Introduction to equivalent expressions":  intro_eq_ex
        },
    ],
    "Solving equations & inequalities": [
        {
            "Linear equations with variables on both sides": s1
        },
        {
            "Linear equations with parentheses": s2
        },
        {
            "Analyzing the number of solutions to linear equations": s3
        },
        {
            "Linear equations with unknown coefficients":  s4
        },
        {
            "Multi-step inequalities": s5
        },
        {
            "Compound inequalities":  s6
        },
    ],
    "Working with units": [
        {
            "Rate conversion": unit1
        },
        {
            "Appropriate units": unit2
        },
        {
            "Word problems with multiple units": unit3
        },
    ]
}

math_1_part_2 = {

    "Linear equations & graphs": [
        {
            "Two-variable linear equations intro": leg1
        },
        {
            "Slope": leg2
        },
        {
            "Horizontal & vertical lines": leg3
        },
        {
            "x-intercepts and y-intercepts": leg4
        }
    ],
    "Forms of linear equations": [
        {
            "Intro to slope-intercept form": fle1
        },
        {
            "Writing slope-intercept equations": fle3
        },
        {
            "Point-slope form": fle4
        },
        {
            "Standard form": fle5
        }
    ],
    "Systems of equations": [
        {
            "Introduction to systems of equations": soe1
        },
        {
            "Solving systems of equations with substitution": soe2
        },
        {
            "Equivalent systems of equations": soe3
        },
        {
            "Solving systems of equations with elimination": soe4
        },
        {
            "Number of solutions to systems of equations": soe5
        },
        {
            "Number of solutions to systems of equations": soe6
        }
    ]
}

math_1_part_3 = {
    "Inequalities (systems & graphs)": [
        {
            "Checking solutions of two-variable inequalities": isg1
        },
        {
            "Modeling with linear inequalities": isg3
        }
    ],
    "Functions": [
        {
            "Evaluating functions": f2
        },
        {
            "Functions and equations": f4
        },
        {
            "Interpreting function notation": f5
        },
        {
            "Determining the domain of a function": f7
        },
        {
            "Recognizing functions": f8
        },
        {
            "Average rate of change word problems": f13
        },
        {
            "Intro to inverse functions": f14
        },
    ],

    "Data distributions": [
        {
            "Displays of distributions": {
                  "Definition": "Some distributions are symmetrical, with data evenly distributed about the mean. Other distributions are 'skewed' with data tending to the left or right of the mean. We sometimes say that skewed distributions have 'tails'.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Joaquin found this histogram. A histogram where the bars are taller on the left side of the graph and smaller on the right side of the graph. Which best describes the shape of the distribution?",
                              "Answer": "Right-skewed",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Summarizing center of distributions (central tendency)": {
                  "Definition": "The mean (average) of a data set is found by adding all numbers in the data set and then dividing by the number of values in the set. \
                  The median is the middle value when a data set is ordered from least to greatest. The mode is the number that occurs most often in a data set.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "What is the arithmetic mean of the following numbers? 8,10,10,10,6,7,8",
                              "Answer": "8",
                              "Type": "Integer",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Comparing distributions": {
                  "Definition": "Some distributions are symmetrical, with data evenly distributed about the mean. Other distributions are 'skewed' with data tending to the left or right of the mean. We sometimes say that skewed distributions have 'tails'.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Minneapolis, Minnesota and Portland, Oregon have very similar latitudes. \
                              (Latitude measures how far north or south a place is, which in turn affects the temperature.) \
                              The histograms below show the daily high temperatures (in degrees Celsius) that were recorded during July 2013 in each city.\
                              A histogram titled, Portland, plots Number of days, versus Temperature, in degrees Celsius, from 15 to 33, in increments of 3 degrees Celsius. Bar heights are approximately as follows. There are no bars between 15 and 21. From 21 to 24, 3. From 24 to 27, 11. From 27 to 30, 6. From 30 to 33, 7. Greater than 33, 4. \
                              A histogram titled, Minneapolis, plots Number of days, versus Temperature, in degrees Celsius, from 15 to 33, in increments of 3 degrees Celsius. Bar heights are approximately as follows. From 15 to 18, 1, From 18 to 21, 0. From 21 to 24, 2. From 24 to 27, 4. From 27 to 30, 6. From 30 to 33, 9. Greater than 33, 9.\
                              Which pieces of information can be gathered from these histograms?",
                              "Answer": "Minneapolis had the coldest daily high temperature of these two cities.",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },        
    ],
    "Sequences": [
        {
            "Introduction to arithmetic sequences": {
                  "Definition": "Sequences are ordered lists of numbers (called 'terms'), like 2,5,8. Some sequences follow a specific pattern that can be used to extend them indefinitely. For example, 2,5,8 follows the pattern 'add 3,' and now we can continue the sequence. Sequences can have formulas that tell us how to find any term in the sequence. For example, 2,5,8,... can be represented by the formula 2+3(n-1)",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "c(n)=-7+6(n-1). Find the 4th in the sequence.",
                              "Answer": "c(4)=11",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Constructing arithmetic sequences": {
                  "Definition": "In arithmetic sequences, the difference between consecutive terms is always the same. We call that difference the common difference.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "h(n)=−31−7(n−1); What is the recursive formula of h(n)?",
                              "Answer": "From the explicit formula, we can tell that the first term of the sequence is -31 and the common difference is -7. Hence, h(n) = h(n-1) - 7",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Introduction to geometric sequences": {
                  "Definition": "In geometric sequences, the ratio between consecutive terms is always the same. We call that ratio the common ratio.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Find an explicit formula for the geometric sequence −9,−18,−36,−72,...",
                              "Answer": "c(n)=-9*2**n",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Modeling with sequences": {
                  "Definition": "Sal solves two word problems about modeling real-world situations with arithmetic and geometric sequences.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Fenyang got 6 rabbits to raise on his farm. From the following month forward, the rabbit population doubled every month.\
                              Let g(n) be the number of rabbits in Fenyang's farm in the nth month since he got the rabbits.g is a sequence. What kind of sequence is it?",
                              "Answer": "Geometric sequence",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        }
        
    ]
}

math_1_part_4 = {

    "Exponents & radicals":[
        {
            "Exponent properties review": {
                  "Definition": "For any base a and any integer exponents n and m, aⁿ⋅aᵐ=aⁿ⁺ᵐ. For any nonzero base, aⁿ/aᵐ=aⁿ⁻ᵐ.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Simplify x^6/x^8 Rewrite the expression in the form of x^n",
                              "Answer": "x^-2",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Exponent properties review": {
                  "Definition": "To find the square root of a number x, we look for a number whose square is x.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "cube root of 125 is?",
                              "Answer": "5",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        }
    ],

    "Exponential growth & decay":[
        {
            "Exponential vs. linear growth": {
                  "Definition": "An exponential function represents the relationship between an input and output, where we use repeated multiplication on an initial value to get the output for any given input. Exponential functions can grow or decay very quickly. Exponential functions are often used to model things in the real world, such as populations, radioactive materials, and compound interest.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "x={-22,-18,-14,-10}, y={8,12,24,60}. Is the relationship linear, exponential, or neither?",
                              "Answer": "neither",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Exponential expressions": {
                  "Definition": "Given the description of a real-world context, we write a calculation of a certain measure. The expression is exponential because it involves repeated multiplication.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "When the Dragons have lost their most recent game, 200 fans buy tickets. \
                              For each consecutive win the Dragons have, the number of tickets fans buy increases by a factor of 1.1 \
                              Write a function that gives the number of tickets t(w) fans buy to Dragons games after the Dragons have had w consecutive wins.",
                              "Answer": "t(w)=200*1.1**w",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Exponential vs. linear growth over time": {
                  "Definition": "If we compare linear and exponential growth, we will see that over time, *any* exponential growth will surpass *any* linear growth, no matter how steep it is.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "The Chewy Candy Company is test marketing a new candy bar in Seoul and Manila. \
                              In Seoul, the company sold 40 candy bars by the end of the first month, and each month the cumulative total number of\
                               candy bars sold increases by 60. \
                               In Manila, the company sold 20 candy bars by the end of the first month, and the cumulative total number of candy bars \
                               sold increases by approximately 80%, percent each month. The company's board assembles \
                               at the end of each month to review the cumulative total number of candies sold in each city. \
                               What is the first month in which the board will see the cumulative total number of candy bars sold in Manila exceeded the cumulative total in Seoul?",
                              "Answer": "6",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 5
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Exponential growth & decay": {
                  "Definition": "Both exponential growth and decay functions involve repeated multiplication by a constant factor.\
                   However, the difference lies in the size of that factor: - In an exponential growth function, the factor is greater than 1, \
                   so the output will increase (or 'grow') over time. - In an exponential decay function, the factor is between 0 and 1, \
                   so the output will decrease (or 'decay') over time.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Does the function model exponential growth or decay? g(x) = 7/3 * 2**x",
                              "Answer": "Growth",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        }
    ],
    "Transformation properties and proofs" : [
        {
            "Rigid transformations overview": {
                  "Definition": "Finding measures after a rigid transformation, like a reflection, is pretty simple! Since the shape and size stay the same, the lengths of corresponding sides and angle measures remain unchanged. Area and perimeter depend on the side lengths, so they stay the same too. So, if we know the measures of the original figure, we can use those same measures for the transformed figure.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Triangle ABC is translated 5 units to the right and 4 units up to create triangle A'B'C'. Triangle ABC is translated 5 units to the right and 4 units up to create triangle A'B'C'. What is the measure of ∠B?",
                              "Answer": "180-80-26=74 degrees",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
    ],
    "Congruence":[
        {
            "Congruent triangles": {
                  "Definition": "Two figures are congruent if and only if we can map one onto the other using rigid transformations. Since rigid transformations preserve distance and angle measure, all corresponding sides and angles are congruent. That means that one way to decide whether a pair of triangles are congruent would be to measure all of the sides and angles.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Two triangles. The first triangle has a seventy-eight degree angle, a fifty-three degree angle, a forty-nine degree angle. The second triangle has a sixty-nine degree angle, a sixty-four degree angle, a forty-seven degree angle. Are the two triangles congruent?",
                              "Answer": "No since all three angles in both triangles, and none of these are equal.",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Theorems concerning triangle properties": {
                  "Definition": "Reflexive property, Symmetric property, Transitive property",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Angles ∠A and ∠C are congruent in △ABC. Which of the following additional statements would allow us to prove that △ABC is equilateral",
                              "Answer": "AB ≅ AC ",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 5
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Working with triangles": {
                  "Definition": "We write the letters of congruent triangles so their order tells us which parts are corresponding.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Triangle A B C and A D E are shown sharing the same point A with sides A D and A B both being three point one units. Sides A E and A C are both three point nine units. Angle A E D is x degrees. Angle A B C is forty-nine degrees. Angle A C B is thirty-six degrees. What is the value of angle x?",
                              "Answer": "∠DAE forms a vertical angle with ∠BAC so the measure of ∠ DAE is equal to the measure of ∠ BAC. △ ABC and △ADE also have two sides equal.\
                               Therefore, △ ABC and △ ADEtriangle are congruent. Congruent triangles also have congruent (equal) angles. \
                               If we superimpose these two triangles, by flipping △ EDA we see that angle EDA corresponds to ∠ACB the measure of angle x is 36",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },

    ],

    "Analytic geometry":[
        {
            "Distance and midpoints": {
                  "Definition": "The formula gives the distance between two points (x1, y1) and (x2,y2) on the coordinate plane: sqrt((x1-x2)**2 + (y1-y2)**2). The formula for the midpoint between them is ((x1+x2)/2, (y1+y2)/2)",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "What is the distance between (-9,-6) and (-2,-2)",
                              "Answer": "sqrt(65)",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Dividing line segments": {
                  "Definition": "figure out the coordinates of a point between two other points that give a certain ratio.",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Point A is at (6,-6) and point C is at (-6,-2). Find the coordinates of point B on AC such that AB = 3/4*AC",
                              "Answer": "by subtracting the coordinates of point A from the coordinates of point C: AC = (-6-6, -2-(-6)) = (-12, 4). Next, calculate the position vector of B by multiplying AC first calculate the vector AC by subtracting the coordinates of point A from the coordinates of point C. AC = (-6-6, -2-(-6)) = (-12, 4). Next, we can calculate the position vector of B by multiplying AC by 3/4. The position vector of B is given by 3/4 * AC = (3/4 * -12, 3/4 * 4) = (-9, 3). Finally, we add the position vector of B to the coordinates of point A to find the coordinates of B. B = (6 + (-9), -6 + 3) = (-3, -3).ition vector of B to the coordinates of point A to find the coordinates of B. B = (6 + (-9), -6 + 3) = (-3, -3).",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Problem solving with distance on the coordinate plane": {
                  "Definition": "We use the distance formula to determine whether a point is inside, outside, or on the circle",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "Point A is at (-5,5) and is the center of circle A.\
                              Point B is at (3,1) and is the center of circle B.\
                              Point P is at (0,0) and is on circles A and B. Which of the following points are on circle A, circle B, or both circles? C(4,-2); D(5,3); E(-2,8).",
                              "Answer": "Using distance formula, PA = 5*sqrt(2), PB = sqrt(10), BC = sqrt(10), AC != PA, AD != AP, BD != BP, AE != AP, BE != BP, we conclude that C is on circle B, and D and E are neither on circle A nor B. ",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        },
        {
            "Parallel & perpendicular lines on the coordinate plane": {
                  "Definition": "To check whether 2 linear equations are perpendicular, parallel or neither, we check the product of slopes of both equations",
                  "QA Queue": [
                          {
                              "Question": "One line passes through the points (-7,5) and (-1,-3). Another line passes through points (0,3) and (3,-1). Are the lines parallel, perpendicular, or neither?",
                              "Answer": "The slopes of both line are equal to -4/3, hence the lines are parallel",
                              "Type": "Narrative",
                              "Difficulty": 4
                          }
                      ],
                  "Rate": 1,
                  }
        }
    ]
}